Guide to the Miguel A. Gandert Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2002 Acquisition, 1980-1999; 2; 2.38; (27 boxes)
  - Varrio San José: Scenes from an Urban Chicano Experience
    - Matted Prints
      - 16 inches by 20 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 20 inches by 24 inches, except where noted.
        - Anthony, Georgia, Joseph, and Ruby Hernandez, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Baby Angel, Fiesta de Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1989; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 33 (Oversize))
        - Baile de Los Matachines, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Couple, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1984 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Happy and the Spook, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1982 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Homeboy with Hand Signal, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Joe Gonzales, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1985 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Juarito with Porkpie Hat, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1985 (Box 31 (Oversize))
        - Lowrider Bicycle, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1984 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Matachine, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Reuben Garcia, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Ruby and Raul, Albuquerque, New Mexico, diptych, 1986-1987 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Sisters Juanita and Anna, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Stepfather and Son, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Stoner and Dimples, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Sonya at 14, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 32 (Oversize))
        - Virgin and Angels, Fiesta de Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1989; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - Unmatted Prints
      Organized under three headings by print size: 11 inches by 14 inches,16 inches by 20 inches, 20 inches by 24 inches.
      - 11 inches by 14 inches
        - Homeboy With Hand Signal, 1982 (Box 34 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 8 (Box 34 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches
        - '51 Chevy, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - '59 Chevy, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Bathers, First Plaza, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - "El Kooks", 1985; 2 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - First Holy Communion, 1986 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Frank Alderete, 1986 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Homeboy Against Wall, 1982 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Juarito With Porkpie Hat, 1985 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Lawrence and Lyla, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1985; 2 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Leroy Romero, 1983; 2 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Little Frankie, 1986 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Mora Family, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Panthers, 1982 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Rene Latmona and Melissa Armijo, undated (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Sleepy, 1983 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Young Matachine, 1989 (Box 35 (Oversize))
        - Youth With Tattooed Lovers, 1986 (Box 35 (Oversize))
      - 20 inches by 24 inches
        - Youth With Tattooed Lovers, 1986 (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - Cibachrome Color Prints, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
      - "Cat Eyes" Melissa Armijo, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1984 (Box 34 (Oversize))
      - Untitled photographs, undated; 6 (Box 34 (Oversize))
  - Tierra O Muerte
    Organized under two headings by print size: 11 inches by 14 inches, and 16 inches by 20 inches and smaller.
    This subseries documents an exhibition that explores land rights disputes in New Mexico, in particular the Tierra Amarilla land grant occupation in 1967. The photographs cheifly include portraits of land rights activists, including Reies López Tijerina and Amador Flores.
    - 11 inches by 14 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
      - Amador Flores, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 36 (Oversize))
      - Child, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 36 (Oversize))
      - Rafael Flores, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 36 (Oversize))
    - 16 inches by 20 inches and smaller, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 20 inches by 24 inches, except where noted.
      - Amador Flores, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Bunkers, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Bunkers, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Bunkers, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, unmatted (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Bunkers, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, diptych, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Child, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Danial Aguilar, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Danny Aguilar, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Daughters of the Revolution, Harmony and Donna Tijerina, Coyote, New Mexico, 1987 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Ditch, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Frederico, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Pedro Archuleta, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Pedro Archuleta, Tierra Amarilla, New Mexico, 1988; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
      - Protest sign and a man with a rifle walking past a Tierra O Muerte sign, diptych, 1988 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Reies Lopéz Tijerina, 20th Anniversary of Tierra Amarilla Courthouse Raid, New Mexico, 1987 July (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Reies Lopéz Tijerina, Coyote, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Reies Lopéz Tijerina, Coyote, New Mexico, 1987 (Box 37 (Oversize))
      - Signs, diptych, undated; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 38 (Oversize))
  - Reflexiones del Corazón, This subseries consists of photographic lithographs, 11 inches by 15 inches, signed by Gandert
    This subseries documents a collaborative project by Gandert with the author Gabriel Melendez and the artist Maria Baca at the Tamarind Institute in Albuquerque, New Mexico. The images depict Hispanic culture in the New Mexico cities of Española and Mora, as well as the Barelas neighborhood of Albuquerque.
    - Adobe, 1992 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Chileros, 1992 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Chimayo, 1992; 3 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Guadalupe, 1992; 2 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Lowriders, 1992; 5 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Morada, 1992; 2 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Mother / Daughter, 1992 (Box 39 (Oversize))
    - Wimpy's, 1992 (Box 39 (Oversize))
  - Nuevo México Profundo, This subseries consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches.
    This subseries consists of work prints for Gandert's co-authored book with Enrique R. Lamadrid, Nuevo México Profundo: Rituals of an Indo-Hispano Homeland. The images and the published work document the religious traditions and customs of the mestizo people of the Upper Rio Grande region of Mexico and New Mexico.
    Each photographic print includes a slip from the publisher of the work, Museum of New Mexico Press, which indicates the figure number and page number where the image appeared in the book.
    Arranged in the order the images appear in the book, followed by prints not included in it.
    - Cerro de Tomé, Tomé, 1993 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - La Victoria del Rey Alfonso, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Juan Diego y su Reina, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Conversión de Moctezuma, Picurís, 1999 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Toritos Capados, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Cuerno Verde y Don Carlos Fernández, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - El Poder de la Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Orgullo del Matachín, Alcalde, 1995 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Monarca y su Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Vuelta de la Malinche, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Abuelo Sumiso, Alcalde, 1996 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - El Abuelo y su Gente, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Abuelo Caído, Alcalde, 1999 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Tres Músicos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Tormento de los Toritos, Alcalde, 1997 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Antes de la Batalla, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Orgullo de Cuerno Verde, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Galento el Embajador, Alcalde, 1994 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Sueño del Abuelo, Picurís, 1992 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Alegría de los Matachines, Picurís, 1996 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Danza del Monarca, Picurís, 1999 (Box 40 (Oversize))
    - Sombra del Monarca, Picurís, 1994 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - El Toro, Picurís, 1996 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - El Gobernador, Picurís, 1992 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Abuela, Picurís, 1996 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Matachines de Noche Buena, Picurís, 1993 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Luminaria, Picurís, 1993 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Malinche y su Abuela, Picurís, 1992 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Músicos y Santos, Picurís, 1995 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - El Comanche David, Talpa, 1996 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Mañanitas del Niño Manuel, Ranchos de Taos, 1995 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Memorias del Cautivo, Talpa, 1996 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Nevada del Año Nuevo, Talpa, 1996 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Baile del Paseado, Talpa, 1997 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Los Cautivos, Talpa, 1995 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Baile del Espantado, Llano Quemado, 1998 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Dulces y Tragos, Talpa, 1997 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Baile Redondo, Llano Quemado, 1997 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Capilla de Talpa, Talpa, 1997 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Floyd y su Tombé, Abiquiú, 1999 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Baile del Borracho, Abiquiú, 1999 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Despedida, Barrio San José, Albuquerque, 1986 (Box 41 (Oversize))
    - Altar de la Esquina, Barrio San José, Albuquerque, 1989 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Bendición de las Aguas, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Entrega de San Ysidro, Atrisco, 1997 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Atrocidades de la Perijundia, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - La Malinche y su Luz, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Ojos al Cielo, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - San Antonio Matachín, San Antonio, 1998 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Soldados de San Antonio, San Antonito, 1988 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Adorando a San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, 1999 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Procesión de San Lorenzo, Bernalillo, 1987 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Adorando a San Luis Gonzaga, San Luis, 1993 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - El Toro Peleando, San Luis, 1993 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Comanchitos de Noche Buena, Bernalillo, 1996 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Las Comanchas y sus Cautivas, Los Griegos, 1997 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Eduardo y la Virgen, Alameda, 1997 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Juan Dieguito, Alameda, 1997 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Moctezuma y su Hija, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Armas de los Tiguas, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Capilla de Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Danza de la Tejida, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Las Malinches, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - General Azteca Chichimeca, Tortugas, 1993 (Box 42 (Oversize))
    - Devociones Guadalupanas, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Pelea de los Abuelos, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Guadalupana del Alma, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Música para Guadalupe, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Plumas en el Viento, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Balazo del Arzobispo, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Quiotes en la Puerta, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Devotos del Cerno, "A" Mountain, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Guadalupano, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Fe y Orgullo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Devoción de los Apaches, Juárez, México, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Danzantes de la Plaza, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Abuelo Charro, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Indito de la Sierra, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Dolor del Abuelo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Vísperas de la Virgen, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Javier y su Hijita, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Orgullo del Guadalupano, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Niños y la Muerte, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Procesión, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Bendiciones del Desierto, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 43 (Oversize))
    - Abuelo y la Muerte, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Soldado de la Virgen, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Danza en el Nuevo Templo, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Al Pie de la Cruz, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Tierra Sagrada, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Sempre Devoto, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Siempre la Cruz, Chimayó, 1993 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Misericordia de Chimayó, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Malinche Tonantzina, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Nuestro Señor de Esquipulas, Chimayó, 1995 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Peregrinos de la Salud, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Santos y Niños, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Edwin y su Tombé, Tomé, 1992 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - La Fe de los Hijos, Tomé, 1999 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Peregrino de la Salud, Tomé, 1999 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Devoción de Mano Lupe, Tomé, 1989 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Ojos al Cielo, Tomé, 1993 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Recuerdos de Robyn, Tomé, 1993 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Escapulario, Tomé, 1992 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Trompetas y Clarines, Tomé, 1992 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Cumbre de la Cruz, Tomé, 1996 (Box 44 (Oversize))
    - Hermanos de la Morada, Tomé, 1992 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Soldado de la Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Familia, Nogales, Sonora, México, 1994 (Box 45 (Oversize))
      Varient title and date in Nuevo México Profundo: Rituals of an Indo-Hispano Homeland: Matachines de Carrizo: Casa, Familia, Hogar, Ranchos de Anapra, 1998.
    - Batalla de Moros y Cristianos, Santa Cruz, 1993 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Pastores a Belén, Belén, 1997 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Abuelos, Amalia, 1986 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Pasos al Calvario, Tomé, 1989 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Danza del Aguila, Talpa, 1998 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Linda Elena, Talpa, 1995 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - David Gonzales, Talpa, 1995 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Palabra de Dios, Chimayó, 1996 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Matachines de Carrizo, Tortugas, 1993 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Peregrino y su Quiote, Tortugas, 1999 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Pedro y su Tierra, Tierra Amarilla, 1988 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Diablos y Santos, Ranchos de Anapra, México, 1998 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Tres Generaciones Cantando, Ranchos de Taos, 1997 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Victor Romero, Albuquerque, 1977 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Melissa Armijo, Eloy Montoya, Richard "El Wino" Madrid, Albuquerque, 1983 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Diego "Lucy" Delgado, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Arco de Triunfo, Bernalillo, 1991 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Agua de la Vida, Tomé, 1993 (Box 45 (Oversize))
    - Images Not Included in the Book
      - Nanille: Danza de la Cautiva, Abiquiú, undated (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Despedida de los Aztecas, Sanctuario de Chimayó, undated (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Untitled photographs, 7 (Box 46 (Oversize))
  - Miscellaneous Prints
    This subseries includes chiefly portraits of individuals from New Mexico and Juárez, México.
    - Matted Prints
      - 11 inches by 14 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
        - Abuelos, Amalia, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 47 (Oversize))
        - Brothers, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 47 (Oversize))
        - Chacon, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 47 (Oversize))
        - Hermano Juan Roybal En Su Oratorio, Las Colonias de Arriba, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 47 (Oversize))
        - Matanza, Las Padillas, New Mexico, 1989 (Box 47 (Oversize))
        - Tattoos, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 47 (Oversize))
        - Young Couple, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mats, 20 inches by 24 inches, except where noted.
        - Abuelos, Amalia, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Black Brothers, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Cuban Indians, Juárez, México, 1987 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Día de Las Madres Protest for Desaparicidos, Tegucigalpa, Honduras, 1984 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Juan Ibarin, Cemetary Caretaker, Acatlán de Juárez, México, 1985 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Juárez, México, 1987 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Matthew Montoya, George Torres, and Melanie Chavez, Santa Barbara, Martineztown, 1992; 1 photographic print, 16 inches by 20 inches, in mat, 20 inches by 26 inches. (Box 50 (Oversize))
        - Monument Cutter, Juárez, México, 1987 (Box 48 (Oversize))
        - Municipal Cemetery, Juárez, México, 1987 (Box 49 (Oversize))
        - Oaxaca, México, 1985 (Box 49 (Oversize))
        - Paul White Eagle, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 49 (Oversize))
        - Roller Derby, 1982 March (Box 49 (Oversize))
        - Rudolfo Macareñas, Amalia, New Mexico, 1987 (Box 49 (Oversize))
        - Twins with Sister, 1986 (Box 49 (Oversize))
        - Woman With Black Nails, Juárez, México, 1987 (Box 49 (Oversize))
    - Unmatted Prints
      Organized under four headings by print size: 8 inches by 10 inches and smaller; 11 inches by 14 inches; 16 inches by 20 inches; 20 inches by 24 inches.
      - 8 inches by 10 inches and smaller
        - Hermano Juan Roybal en su Oratorio, Las Colonias de Arriba, New Mexico, 1988; 3 (Box 51)
        - Morada, near Pecos, 1989; 2 (Box 51)
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 2 (Box 51)
      - 11 inches by 14 inches
        - Mickey Mouse Balloons / Being With It, 1979 September (Box 52 (Oversize))
        - Nietos de Don Simón, Civic Center, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 52 (Oversize))
        - Tattoos, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1988 (Box 52 (Oversize))
        - Teresa Gutiérrez, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 52 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 10 (Box 52 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 11 (Box 53 (Oversize))
      - 16 inches by 20 inches
        - Family from Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1985 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Horacio Martinez, Martineztown, New Mexico, 1992 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Juan Roybal, Lower las Colonias, New Mexico, 1989, undated; 3 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Juárez, México, 1987; 2 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Mexican Nationals, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Morada, near Pecos, 1989 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Lowriders / Reflexiones del Corazón, 1992 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Paul White Eagle, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1986 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Richard Mares and Seferino Lucero, Rio Bravo Boulevard, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983; 2 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Silva's Grocery Store, Barelas, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1983 (Box 54 (Oversize))
        - Truchas, New Mexico, 1990 (Box 55 (Oversize))
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 9 (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - 20 inches by 24 inches
        - Teresa Gutiérrez, Juárez, México, 1992 (Box 50 (Oversize))
    - Cibachrome Color Prints
      Organized under three headings by print size: 8 inches by 10 inches, 11 inches by 14 inches, and 18.5 inches by 23.5 inches.
      - 8 inches by 10 inches
        - Untitled photographs, undated; 21 (Box 51)
      - 11 inches by 14 inches, This group of material consists of photographic prints, 11 inches by 14 inches, in mats, 16 inches by 20 inches.
        - Untitled photograph, undated (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - 18.5 inches by 23.5 inches
        - Santa Monica, California, undated (Box 50 (Oversize))
- November 2003 Acquisition, 1982-2001; 3; 5.34; (32 boxes)
  The November 2003 Acquisition documents Gandert's projects and exhibitions, 1982-2001. It chiefly consists of photographic prints, contact sheets, printed material, and audiovisual material.
  Organized into two subseries: Photographs and Printed Material.
  - Photographs
    This subseries is organized under two headings: Nuevo México Profundo and Miscellaneous Prints.
    - Nuevo México Profundo
      Organized under two headings: Unmatted Prints and Color Prints.
      This group of black-and-white and color photographic prints are images that appeared in Gandert's co-authored book with Enrique R. Lamadrid, Nuevo México Profundo: Rituals of an Indo-Hispano Homeland. The image and the work document the religious traditions and customs of the mestizo people of the Upper Rio Grande region of Mexico and New Mexico.
      - Unmatted Prints
        Organized under five headings by print size: 5 inches by 7 inches, 8 inches by 10 inches, 11 inches by 14 inches, 16 inches by 20 inches, and 20 inches by 24 inches.
        - 5 inches by 7 inches
          Arranged alphabetically by location.
          - Abiquiú, 1999, undated; 2 (Box 56)
          - Amalia, 1986 (Box 56)
          - Alcalde, circa 1994-1997; 18 (Box 56)
          - Atrisco, undated; 2 (Box 56)
          - Barelas, undated; 7 (Box 56)
          - Barrio San José, 1986-1989; 2 (Box 56)
          - Belén, 1997; 2 (Box 56)
          - Bernalillo, undated; 4 (Box 56)
          - Cerro de Tomé, 1989-1999; 11 (Box 56)
          - Chimayó, 1996, undated; 8 (Box 56)
          - Juárez, México, 1993-1998, undated; 9 (Box 56)
          - Los Griegos, 1991 (Box 56)
          - Picurís, circa 1992-1999; 16 (Box 56)
          - Rancho de Taos, 1996 (Box 56)
          - San Antonito, circa 1988-1989; 5 (Box 56)
          - San Luis, undated (Box 56)
          - Talpa, 1996-1997, undated; 6 (Box 56)
          - Tortugas, 1996-1999, undated; 20 (Box 56)
        - 8 inches by 10 inches
          Arranged chronologically followed by untitled images.
          - Fe y Orgullo, Juárez, México, 1993 (Box 56)
          - El Toro Peleando, San Luis, 1993 (Box 56)
          - Los Cautivas, Talpa, 1995 (Box 56)
          - Comanchitos, Talpa, 1995 (Box 56)
          - El Espantado, Talpa, 1995 (Box 56)
          - Juan Diego y su Reina, Juárez, México, 1995 (Box 56)
          - Linda Elena, Talpa, 1995 (Box 56)
          - Músicos y Santos, Picurís, 1995; 2 (Box 56)
          - Orgullo del Matachín, Alcalde, 1995 (Box 56)
          - El Comanche David, Talpa, 1996 (Box 56)
          - Guadalupana del Alma, Tortugas, 1996 (Box 56)